[soft instrumental music]
[music continues]
[Anne] I almost got married once.
Wentworth held my heart.
But he was a sailor
without rank or fortune.
And I was persuaded to give him up.
[music slows down, then stops]
[playful instrumental music]
[Anne] Now I'm single and thriving.
I spend my time drinking fine wines,
enjoying warm baths…
and lying face down on my bed.
Like I said, thriving.
Who needs romance
when one has… family?
[playful music continues]
My father.
He's never met a reflective surface
he didn't like.
Vanity is the beginning and end
of his character.
Also the middle.
"Sir Walter Elliot,
born March 1st, 1760."
"Man of consequence,
known for his exquisite jawline."
[Anne] He is the sole object
of his own warmest respect and devotion.
[sighs] One's family is only escapable
by two things,
marriage and death.
Both seem unlikely
in the immediate future.
"Married July 15th, 1784, to Jane."
My mother.
-I miss her.
-[Sir Walter] "Jane died in 1801."
"By her, Sir Walter issued
three children."
My sisters.
[Sir Walter] "Elizabeth, celebrated beauty
and Somerset's
most fashion-forward luminary."
Elizabeth, the eldest.
[Sir Walter] "Mary,
married to Charles Musgrove,
heir to the superior Uppercross estate."
Mary, the youngest.
"And Anne, born August 9th, 1787."
And me, middle child,
the crack in his looking glass.
Shame there wasn't anything nice
we could think to add about you, Anne.
Thanks for trying.
You're welcome.
I wanted to leave you out entirely,
but Daddy thought
people might think you had died.
-Debt collectors.
-[Elizabeth] Daddy. Daddy!
[Anne] The one thing my father loves more
than himself is spending money.
It was always going to run out one day.
-Daddy…
-Daddy's broke, princess.
Playtime's over.
Oh!
[lawyer] There, there, Sir Walter.
Lots of people face debt
at some point in their lives.
You must retrench.
You have no choice.
I've drawn up a vigorous plan of economy.
The most necessary reductions
are underlined.
Meet my mother's best friend
and unflinching speaker of truth.
Lady Russell took it on herself
to give me advice on every topic
as she felt my mother would have.
Always insightful and helpful.
With one… notable exception.
Some people don't have homes or food.
Try to put this into perspective.
Mr. Shepherd,
if I was interested in gaining perspective
by thinking of the poor,
I'd ask you the rate
charged by your barber.
Don't ask me to change things
by seeing them differently.
See things my way,
then change them until they are different.
Perhaps we need only stop
giving to charities.
Do we do that?
Jane would be ashamed.
She begged me to protect her daughters
from their father's excessive excesses
and I have failed.
Your arrogance will bankrupt them all.
Father,
true reputation comes
from honesty, integrity, compassion,
acceptance of responsibility
for the welfare of others.
Anne, we're speaking
of something substantial.
Try to keep up.
Why not downsize
and move somewhere cheaper?
Bath is lovely.
And the spas there
will work wonders for your skin.
And what of Kellynch Hall?
Just the other day
I met a wealthy naval officer
who would pay a handsome rent
for a house like Kellynch.
I will not have a Navy man in my house.
-They're all ugly.
-Admiral Croft is quite handsome.
Admiral? What right has the British Navy
to bring persons of obscure birth
into undue distinction?
Only God has the right to bestow rank.
What good is a title
if you have to earn it?
What good is anything
Admiral Croft is a fine gentleman.
His wife told me about a brother
who lived among us a few years back.
He was also a naval officer.
What was his name? Uh, Wellington?
Weathers? Winslow?
You mean Wentworth?
-[Mr. Shepherd] Wentworth? Yes.
-Anne, darling.
In truth, I can hardly remember
who you are speaking of.
[Sir Walter] You really think
my skin will do well in Bath?
[Lady Russell] Oh, yes.
-[Lady Russell] Yes.
-[knock on door]
Sweetheart… it's been seven years.
Eight.
You couldn't possibly still feel--
I do.
Frederick Wentworth was the only person,
save you and my mother,
who ever really saw me.
And understood me.
And loved me.
Aw.
And the only one I wanted to--
Exchange calling cards with?
Well put.
You lied when you told me
time would heal me of my pain.
-You're angry with me.
-I'm angry with myself.
For… being persuaded.
For not seeing then
what I see so clearly now.
That I would have been
a far happier woman in keeping him
than I have been in giving him up.
Hmm.
I'm sorry. The truth is,
marriage is transactional for women.
Our basic security is on the line.
I could not let you throw yourself away
on a man with no rank,
no fortune,
nothing but himself to recommend him.
That was the part I liked.
Besides, all of his confidence
was justified. He is rich now.
And a captain.
Then, why haven't you heard from him?
Because…
I broke his heart.
And he knew why.
I thought I was protecting you.
I was wrong.
I see that now.
And I'm sorry.
[sighs]
You will find the one
that's meant for you.
The one who loves you enough
to fight for you.
Darling, I admire how strongly
you feel about it,
but at some point, you have to move on.
I fear Wentworth is a ship
that has sailed,
so I say this with love.
Abandon all hope.
[receding footsteps]
It's true, he hasn't written to me.
But… I knew he wouldn't.
[sniffs]
He respects himself too much to beg.
He didn't fight for me because
he could never value
a love that wasn't offered freely.
I'm sure he's put it all behind him.
I, on the other hand,
have kept it painfully in front of me.
[playful instrumental music]
The first note he passed me in church.
The playlist he made me.
One lock of hair from him.
And one from his horse, Sampson,
whom I scarcely knew.
And this cow bell,
whose sad, empty knell
best captures my melancholy.
[clangs]
Eight years of it.
He's been all over.
And the Navy adores him.
"Frederick Wentworth turns a pretty penny
aboard the Laconia."
"Frederick Wentworth
rescues a beached whale
as onlookers weep."
And yet… no marriage announcement.
Nothing at all to indicate
he's since been in any way
attached to another.
In other words…
hope springs eternal.
[laughter in the room]
[Elizabeth] As we're moving,
I need to think about my Bath persona.
I think Bath Elizabeth should be
less sophisticated than London Elizabeth,
but not as free-spirited
as country Elizabeth.
Penelope, what do you think?
You'll accompany the Elliots north,
Mrs. Clay?
Oh, I wouldn't dream of imposing.
Of course you would.
You dream of nothing but.
And lucky for you, I wouldn't dream
of going anywhere without you.
Mrs. Penelope Clay,
widowed, though she never speaks of it.
He was a corpse when they met, so perhaps
the transition escaped her attention.
Lady Russell worries
that Mrs. Clay has designs on my father,
but I don't think she's his type.
Besides, can you actually imagine
my father marrying down?
Oh, you must come,
if your father can spare you.
Mr. Shepherd, do you think
you can spare Penelope?
Hmm.
Good, fine, exquisite, Sir Walter.
[chuckles]
You really are too generous
for your own good! [laughs]
[Sir Walter] We'll need
your pleasant company
to make amends for the many plain faces
we shall have to endure in Bath.
Now, Sir Walter,
not everyone was made to be handsome.
Your beauty will shine
twice as brightly amongst them.
It is said if you're a five in London,
you're a ten in Bath.
Well, just think,
you and Elizabeth,
you'll be thirteens there.
[Sir Walter and Elizabeth laugh]
You'll be at least a six, Anne.
[Mr. Shepherd slurps]
[Elizabeth] Anyway, Anne won't be
joining us for quite some time.
What?
I got a letter from Mary today.
She's ill again and needs you
at Uppercross immediately.
I know you barely tolerate her.
Still, it's a more positive reaction
than anyone else has towards her,
making you the logical choice.
[Mr. Shepherd slurps]
Fabulous.
[Elizabeth] Make sure the nice linens
are hidden before the admiral arrives.
Why? Do you think they'll steal them?
I don't like the idea
of their naked skin on my sheets.
It might bring you luck.
And hide the ledgers.
I don't want anyone assuming my identity.
I don't think anyone wants your credit
at this point, Father.
Oh, and remind them, in a gentle way,
never to go anywhere near my rose garden.
Oh, yes, please. And the shrubberies.
I don't like the idea of my shrubberies
being enjoyed by others.
Use the scratchy linen,
don't set foot in the garden
and don't look at the shrubberies.
Any other hospitable words?
That is all. Oh, but please make sure
every room is spotless before they arrive.
I don't want rumors circulating
about dust.
[playful music stops]
[melancholic music plays]
[birds chirping]
[Admiral Croft] Oh.
It's even more incredible
than we were told.
You mustn't worry,
we'll be excellent tenants.
Do you always travel with your husband?
Oh, yes. And no one will ever stop me.
[Anne chuckles]
I've crossed the Atlantic four times,
gone once to the East Indies
and back again.
Cork, Lisbon, Gibraltar…
The happiest moments of my life
have been spent aboard a ship.
You're very lucky.
[Mrs. Croft] You'll see
when you're in love.
You know, Anne,
Mrs. Croft's baby brother is a bachelor.
He's a captain in the Navy,
quite successful.
Edward, please don't.
A woman without a husband
is not a problem to be solved.
-I knew your brother, actually.
-[Mrs. Croft] Did you?
-Oh, how wonderful.
-[Anne chuckles]
Perhaps we can all have dinner together
once he joins us.
Joins you?
-[Mrs. Croft] His ship just docked.
-[Admiral] He'll be here in two days.
These gardens are so beautiful.
[music continues]
I wonder how he feels as to a meeting.
If he'd wished to see me before now,
he need not have waited.
He's angry still, I'm sure.
What if I've been wrong?
What if he's been pining for me
day and night all these years?
[music rising]
[coachman] Whoa there!
Here you are.
[music slows down]
[Mary] Can someone help me?
Mary is preferable to Elizabeth
in that she's a total narcissist.
So, conversing with her
requires very little energy
and can be great fun.
Once, I went an entire 24 hours
speaking exclusively in Italian.
She only noticed
when I asked her to pass the sale.
She's so wrapped up in her own suffering
that, until I clear my throat,
she won't even notice I'm here.
Watch.
First, she'll complain
about some unidentifiable ailment
that has her on the verge of death.
Next, she'll rail against her husband
for not caring for her properly.
And then she will assault her in-laws,
who constantly disrespect her
and must secretly despise her.
[clears throat]
I'm monstrously relieved you're here.
I don't know what it is.
A bug of some sort.
I can't move. I'm on the verge of death.
Charles is out shooting,
not a single caring word on his way out.
Hmm.
And my in-laws sent me
that lovely bouquet.
Isn't that sweet?
They'll rot, and I'll feel worse
than if they hadn't sent anything at all.
Hmm.
How unkind is it
to remind a dying person of decay?
Anne, these people hate me.
The children are monsters,
the house is drafty
and nobody cares
about the theater anymore.
Precisely, Anne, yes.
-Anne!
Meet my sisters in-law,
Henrietta and Louisa Musgrove.
They are beautiful in every way.
-Anne!
-[Anne] Girls!
We were so glad
when Mary said that you'd come.
We've been positively giddy all week.
You must promise to spend
every waking second with us, no excuses.
[Mary clears throat]
When you aren't attending
to your sister of course.
-How are you feeling, Mary?
-You haven't asked me how I'm feeling.
-I just did.
-[Mary] I'm close to death.
I can feel my organs decomposing.
-[giggling]
-Same as yesterday, then.
Encouraging that, though her organs rot,
her personality remains as fresh as ever.
[all laugh]
Anne, you must dine with us every night,
delight us with your playing,
because we will do nothing
but dance and sing and laugh.
[kids] Marie Antoinette!
[Anne] How dare you speak my name,
you naughty subjects!
Careful, boys,
ladies don't like to be trampled.
And your mother has a headache.
To have things near your face
when you don't know where they've been!
We're hungry, Marie Antoinette.
-Well, let them eat cake!
-[Charles] No cake until after supper.
There'll be special guests tonight.
We'll meet Admiral Croft and his wife.
She's bringing her brother,
Frederick Wentworth.
Just arrived this morning, we hear.
A gallant captain!
I heard he once redirected
an entire flotilla
to save a beached whale.
[Mary] I had no idea
you were fond of whales.
[chuckles]
-Have you ever met Captain Wentworth?
-In passing, long ago.
-Is it true he's devastatingly handsome?
-He has a kind face, yes.
And is it true he actually listens
when women speak?
He listens.
He listens with his whole body.
It's… electrifying.
Well, then, he sounds like
just the man for you.
-I insist you pursue him.
-Louisa…
No, no. I've made up my mind, Anne.
No more hiding your light
underneath a bushel.
You are very sweet, but I'm not interested
in receiving instruction
on where to put my light.
Or my bushel.
[giggles]
Tell me, honestly, why aren't you married?
I'm waiting to fall in love.
All right, here's what you'll do.
At dinner, you'll sit right next to him.
I'll sit right next to him.
Then, you'll pretend
not to know a thing about anything.
Men like explaining things.
Tell him you've never used utensils,
ask him to teach you how to hold them.
Is this how they're teaching courtship
these days?
Then, just when he starts
to seem interested,
don't respond to a single thing he says.
As though you're a ghost.
He'll be hooked. [giggles]
So, then, just be myself.
Oh no. Don't do that until at least
the second year of marriage.
That may not be the worst advice.
-Mary!
-Charles. What happened?
Mary, help. He's hurt his arm.
-[Mary] What has he done?
-He fell from a tree.
Of course this happens the one evening
people of interest are set to visit.
He didn't fall on purpose, Mary.
Someone will have to stay with him.
I'll bring you back some plum pudding.
So, it's the mother who must stay, then.
It's not enough
I brought these humans into the world,
I must now miss dinners
on account of them.
This is just my luck.
If there is anything disagreeable,
men are sure to get out of it.
Mary, my sweet, he's hurt.
And you aren't feeling
quite yourself either.
Oh no, that's cleared up entirely.
I'm sure the Crofts will come again.
Oh, I hate my life.
If it's really bothering you,
I'm happy to stay with you.
That goes without saying.
Of course. I'm not gonna stay alone.
Wouldn't it be hard to be away from
little Charles when he's in so much pain?
No, Louisa.
Please understand.
The thing about me is, I am an empath.
I'm actually the least equipped to be
with my children when they're suffering
because I feel it so deeply.
It's much better for me to be away.
Life is so much easier for people
like Anne who aren't so sensitive.
Mary, would you like me to stay alone
while you go to dinner?
That's so kind.
I'll bring you back some plum pudding.
And perhaps a crust of bread
and some gruel?
Don't worry, Anne, I'll talk you up.
I'll paint such a pretty picture, he'll be
ready to propose by morning. Promise.
[door closes]
[slow melancholic music]
[music continues]
[sighs]
If only I could talk to him.
[music becomes playful]
Frederick!
[woman] Oh.
Oh!
Oh. Ouch.
[dog barks in distance]
[gasps]
[sighs]
Perfect.
[music stops]
[screaming and laughter]
Thanks again for last night, Anne.
I really think
you would have liked Captain Wentworth.
Um, this jam is too soggy.
I'd rather not have jam at all
if it is to be soggy.
I want to be a captain.
Absolutely not.
No nephew of mine will be a sailor.
Don't you know
they have to wear silly hats?
Anne, please, I can't endure
the sound of laughter before noon.
And the rules are
you must grow a silly mustache.
[kids laugh]
-Mm.
-[Mary] No.
[Charles] Wentworth doesn't have
a mustache, but he is quite impressive.
Handsome, intelligent, rich.
-[child] Do it again!
-[Anne] Oh, look at me.
I'm Captain Wentworth
and I am very impressive!
I'm rich and I'm handsome
and everybody loves me!
And I'm a sailor!
[Charles] Uh, Captain,
meet Mary's sister, Anne.
-Actually, we… We've met.
-We've met.
-Oh
-Long ago, before I was rich.
But not before I was handsome.
You look… old.
-I didn't mean that.
-What did you mean?
Old… Older… than you used to look.
-Your face has matured.
-Small price to pay for a life of purpose.
-Are you implying my life lacks purpose?
-How would I know?
Your hair remains intact.
Your hair is also
suitably appropriate.
-Thank you.
-So, then, you two really have met.
-Fleetingly.
-And yet memorable in its fleetingness.
Shall we go?
-We shall.
-Yes.
Oh.
[Anne sighs]
-What?
-You still have jam on your face.
[laughs]
[slow instrumental music]
[indistinct chatter]
My dress is soaked.
[Louisa] I told you he'd be back, Anne.
Why don't you sit next to him?
[Anne, sighing] Louisa.
[indistinct]
[music continues]
-Do come through here.
-[Mrs. Croft] Thank you so much.
Captain Wentworth,
I'm going to keep you next to me.
[Frederick] Certainly.
Louisa.
How perfect.
[music stops]
[playful instrumental music]
-[Louisa] I'll sit next to you.
-I'll get your chair.
Thank you very much.
[people chatting indistinctly]
[loud scraping]
Light under bushel, check.
[people chatting indistinctly]
-By the stem?
-By the stem.
Quite the upgrade.
From what?
From whoever didn't want
to sit next to me.
Now, tell me, do you have
the same trouble with spoons?
Thank you.
[Frederick] Thank you.
[Louisa] Thank you very much.
Enjoying it. It's delicious.
[both laugh]
Captain Wentworth was telling me
how he almost died at sea.
My, captain! What made you decide
on such a risky profession?
When I first left shore,
I was in great need of distraction.
For that, the constant threat on my life
was useful.
In fact, I was in such despair,
there were times I almost wished for it.
Would it be too bold to ask
the source of such desperation?
A woman.
Well, then, her loss.
Now, though,
I've had my fill of excitement.
I long for absolute boredom
to lull me back to myself.
And by that you mean a wife?
Mother!
I mean, people and things
I can be quiet with, yes.
Who better to be quiet with than a wife?
Mother!
-Are you in the market for a wife, boy?
-Father!
No, you found me out.
Here I am, ashore,
looking to make a foolish match.
A little kindness, a strong mind,
a few compliments to the Navy,
and I'm a lost man.
Anyone between the ages of 18 and 80
may have me for the asking.
[laughter]
Almost anyone.
Charles wanted to marry me first.
[Mrs. Musgrove] What's that, Anne?
Um…
Uh, just speaking of marriage.
Um… [clears throat]
Remember how Charles wanted
to marry me before he married Charles?
I mean Mary.
Sorry, Charles, um…
Before she married…
Sorry, before he, of course he,
came to his senses and married Mary.
Please go on. You'd like us to understand
that your brother-in-law
once preferred you to your sister?
-That's true, yes.
-It's true.
Yes, it's quite right. There, there.
[soft piano music]
Wentworth isn't very gallant to you, Anne.
He said you were so altered
he hardly recognized you.
Don't worry, I stood up for you.
I told him your eye got so infected
it swelled shut for a week
and then we all called you Blackbeard.
I suppose that isn't sticking up for you
so much as just saying a thing.
Yes, I suppose it was more that.
[indistinct]
More, Anne, please. Play for us, maestro.
[soft piano music resumes]
[piano fades]
[melancholic instrumental music]
[Anne] He was so distant last night.
I'd prefer open hostility.
His cold politeness and ceremonious grace
are worse than anything.
"Beg your pardon, Miss Elliot,
is this your chair?"
[screams]
Love me, you idiot!
Love me or kill me now! I can't bear it!
[clears throat]
Lady Macbeth.
Act three, scene four.
She'll buy it.
Oh, right.
How are you this morning, Mary?
I'm still dizzy from watching
Wentworth spin Louisa around all evening.
Or as much as he could manage
with you plonk-plonking sad-sack tunes.
"Für Elise" happens to be
a great dance song
for those sophisticated enough
to explore less traditional movements.
And how would you dance to Beethoven?
Alone in my room with a bottle of red.
Frederick will surely propose to Louisa.
Then they'll be married
and then Louisa will be happy forever.
Why must everyone always assume
that all women want
is to be chosen by any eligible bachelor?
Because marriage is the greatest blessing
that life can offer.
Where are your children?
How should I know?
Nobody tells you when you're young
that life keeps going.
It keeps going whether you approve
of the progression or not.
[sighs] And, eventually,
you find yourself wondering,
"How did I end up here?"
A heartbeat ago, there were no two souls
more in rhythm than Wentworth and I.
Now we're strangers.
Worse than strangers.
[sighs] We're exes.
[James] Auntie Anne.
-Where are you?
-Come and play.
[kids scream]
[romantic instrumental music]
Ha!
Marie Antoinette, Marie Antoinette,
the people don't want you.
They don't want to have a queen anymore.
How dare you speak to me that way!
You are my subjects.
Bad queen!
Bad queen? Bad subject!
-Wait, what's the words again?
-Vive la révolution.
Vive la revolution!
Haha! This is mine. This is my crown.
[kids scream]
[Anne] How dare you take my crown!
-[kids laugh]
-[Anne] You got me!
-Okay. That's enough! Boys!
-Bad queen!
-[boys yell]
-[Anne] No!
That was quite reckless.
The boy could have been hurt.
You're right. I'm sorry.
We got carried away.
-Save it for Robespierre.
-Frederick!
I'm doing my best.
Your best? About what?
About you and me.
I don't want you to be angry.
What would you want me to be?
[Mary] I'm just too kind, Anne,
that's my problem.
I give all of my attention to others
and then I suffer for it.
[in Italian] How far is the Colosseum?
Mmm, you're right,
but how do I prioritize self-care
with everyone around me
constantly bidding for my attention?
[in Italian] One cappuccino, please!
What I've realized is
I need to fall in love with myself first,
and then I can truly love those around me,
and that's all there is to it.
Oh!
[in Italian] How much is that porcupine
in the window?
-[Mary] What's behind me?
-[in Italian] Cheese roll?
Are you trying to go somewhere without me
and gesturing to keep it a secret?
We are going for a-a walk, Mary.
-Very long walk.
-Through the woods.
-You hate nature.
-You hate moving your legs.
You made us carry you home last time.
So, you assume because I hate something
I don't want to do it?
Um…
[sighs] Great.
[insects buzz]
[giggling]
[Mary] Bugs everywhere.
-Anne.
-Hmm?
There's something
I've been meaning to ask you,
but I'm ashamed.
What is it?
You remember
when Captain Wentworth first came
and I encouraged you to pursue him?
Yes.
Well, that was before I knew him,
of course.
And I genuinely hoped
that you two would be a match.
Not that you seem at all interested.
-Don't I?
-[Louisa] You barely look at him.
And now you'd like him for yourself?
He's everything.
You seem surprised.
I suppose I am. I thought you two were--
I don't know how he feels,
but I'm falling in love.
I've thought quite a lot about how
I would feel were our roles reversed.
I might be hurt, perhaps even jealous,
but I can honestly say that any sorrow
for myself would be entirely eclipsed
by the pleasure I would take
in seeing you happy.
-You're trying very hard here.
-[Louisa laughs]
Is it working?
[Anne chuckles]
I don't understand
why you think you need my permission
if you say I barely look at him.
Because it's the way
you barely look at him.
I know what I'm watching and it's more
than two people who have merely met.
What you're seeing is… the past.
Look, I believe
this man could be my future.
[distant whistle]
[melancholic instrumental music]
And a frigate is larger
than a sloop, correct?
-Someone's been studying.
-[Frederick] Very good.
A sloop is crewed by 130 men or so,
while a frigate can carry 140 to 200.
Depending on whether
it's fifth or sixth rate, I suppose.
[Frederick chuckles]
"Now May with all her smiling trains
of vernal beauty sticks--"
That's more than enough poetry.
You know how much I detest metaphor.
[chuckling] Sorry, Mary, I'd forgotten.
My mind is like a sieve.
Which is a simile, not a metaphor.
Fine. My mind is a sieve.
Whatever your mind is,
stop using words imaginatively.
I can't bear it.
[Henrietta] Look! We could drop in
on Harry Hayter.
Perhaps he's worked up the nerve
to propose to me.
Not that I had any intention
for leading us in this direction.
No, absolutely not.
I will not enter the Hayter house.
I'm sure to contract
some terrible illness.
Mary, don't be ridiculous.
Is it ridiculous to care for one's health?
Households employing fewer
than five servants are unsanitary.
Please don't judge us
by our poor relations, captain.
It's unpleasant having such connections.
Just to be clear, you disapprove of him
for your sister-in-law
because he is not wealthy enough?
[Mary] I know.
It really is awful, isn't it?
Shall we?
[ducks quacking]
[playful instrumental music]
[Louisa] It's that Elliot pride.
I find it detestable.
To know Sir Walter, one might believe
the title of Baronet second only to King.
Lord knows how sweet Anne
came out of that lot.
We all so wish Charles had married her
instead. Don't you agree?
-Don't let her fool you.
-What do you mean?
Anne Elliot has as much pride as the rest.
It just takes a different form.
I don't understand.
Next time you witness Miss Elliot
quietly installing herself
on the outskirts of some social situation,
consider whether she might assume
this vantage in order to judge everyone.
Harshly.
Anne Elliot is pure kindness.
You don't know her like I do.
You are the one
who is pure kindness, Louisa,
and for this reason
you always assume the best of others.
The truest evidence of an inferior mind
is to allow oneself to be persuaded away
from one's deepest convictions.
[Louisa] What deepest convictions?
I won't have you speak ill of Anne.
She is too dear to me.
I don't know what happened between you
and I'm not asking.
I do see the best in her,
and I implore you to look for it too.
Please forgive me. I've been too harsh.
Thank you for calling me to task.
If I forgive you,
will you teach me how to read a sextant?
-[Frederick] On such short acquaintance?
-I'm free this evening.
[both laugh]
[Frederick] Shall we wander?
[slow playful music]
[sighs]
[music stops]
There's nothing worse
than thinking your life is ruined
and then realizing
you've got much, much further to fall.
[music resumes]
Like I said.
-[birds cawing]
-[Anne groans softly]
[sighs deeply]
[indistinct chatter]
[Mrs. Croft] How lovely to see you.
-She's injured.
-Shall I ask her?
Anne? Anne, may we offer you a ride home?
-Thank you. I'm quite all right.
-Anne, you've clearly hurt your foot.
It's hardly ten minutes out of our way.
Please, come.
You're so kind.
And I'm so enjoying the fresh air.
Must you be so proud?
Please, let this be easy.
[sighs]
[slow melancholic music]
[kids screaming]
James.
Come here.
I need a favor from you.
Do you think you can help?
I need you to hug me so tightly
that I can't feel my body anymore.
-Do you think you can do that?
-Mm-hmm.
[Anne exhales slowly]
James, tea time.
Anne. Anne, we are going to Lyme.
Tomorrow.
It's been decided.
We'll spend the night by the sea.
To Lyme? Why?
Captain Wentworth wants us
to meet some of his Navy friends.
-I'm not quite up for a trip, I'm afraid.
-What?
Anne, we're going to Lyme tomorrow.
I need 24 hours away from the terrors.
No, wait.
Mary, I'm not--
No. You're always out to ruin my fun
and I won't have it.
I need a holiday, and I need you with me
to have someone to talk at
when the others stop feeling obligated.
Shockingly self-aware.
[pensive instrumental music]
[seagulls crying]
[waves lapping]
[Henrietta laughs]
[indistinct chatter]
Captain, this is Anne Elliot.
Anne Elliot.
Captain Harville.
Pleasure to meet you.
Please excuse me.
Now, you are a fan of poetry.
Or is that just a rumor?
You seem to know more of me
than I can hardly be comfortable with.
Forgive me, I'm just hatching a plot.
-You see our friend over there?
-Yes.
[Harville] Captain Benwick.
Now, Captain Benwick has also
considerable taste in reading.
But he has fallen into a sadness.
I wondered if you might
take a moment to talk to him?
I can build a house out of driftwood,
but don't ever ask me about the Greeks.
[Anne laughs] What's the source
of his sorrow?
Home from Troy and there's another man
in his bed? [laughs]
Sorry, Agamemnon joke.
He was engaged to my sister Fanny.
And they were very much in love.
And she died while he was at sea,
just before they were set to be married.
I'm so sorry.
They say the universe always has a plan.
[Anne sighs]
-[Harville] So, will you? Speak to him.
-I'd be happy to.
Though I'm not sure I'm the messenger
the universe has in mind.
Trust me, it's never wrong.
All that is meant for one
is meant to find one.
I promise.
[Frederick laughs]
[indistinct chatter]
And while you're at it,
convince our friend Wentworth
that he'd be a fool
to ignore the Navy much longer.
-I hate to see a talent wasted.
-[laughs]
If only I had influence.
Tonight at dinner? You get him drunk.
I'll smuggle him aboard.
Perhaps you should ask Louisa.
I'm asking you.
Shall we?
[Harville] Not tempted
to have a dip in the water, are you?
Thank you. Promise?
Come on, Mary.
[laughter]
Wentworth, of course, refused to admit
that he had got the coordinates wrong.
Captain Wentworth is very stubborn.
Stubborn indeed.
He could be an admiral some day,
great service to the Crown
and all that it holds dear,
but instead he'd rather fart around inland
for the rest of his life.
Oh, let the man fart where he likes.
I would like to have a family one day.
As you well know,
the wife of a sailor pays a tax
for her husband's chosen path.
It is but a small fee.
Constant worry.
I'd hate to ask that of anyone.
That's ridiculous.
No life is without worry.
Harville is right.
Anne.
Your future wife will be perfectly capable
of managing her own feelings.
Don't patronize her by deciding for her
what worries she can and cannot endure.
Who knows?
Perhaps she'll even be forging
her own adventures at home.
[Harville] Right, who wants more wine?
[Henrietta] Yes. Yes.
-Yeah? Okay, good.
-Yes. Yes.
[people chat indistinctly]
[Anne] Lord Byron.
"She was my life's unerring light."
"That quench'd,
what beams shall break my night."
Yes. [sighs] He's got me
through a self-pitying night or two.
I often think
it is the great misfortune of poetry
that it's seldom enjoyed safely
by those capable
of enjoying it completely.
Only people who know loss
can really appreciate Byron.
But those people
should only taste him sparingly.
Otherwise, they'll be left
more deeply in their sorrow.
-Then, what are those people meant to do?
-[Anne chuckles]
Honestly, I've been trying
to work that out for eight years now.
I can only tell you
what I must repeat to myself daily.
You're young. You don't know
what the future has in store.
You will rally,
and you will be happy again.
-Perhaps you're right.
-[Anne] I know I am.
-Thank you, Miss Elliot.
-[chuckles]
[seagull crying]
[romantic instrumental music]
I'm only saying, the lower ranks
are taxed disproportionately.
[playful music]
-[Louisa] Who is that?
-Pardon me. I think I'm in your way.
Perhaps you can correct that.
Perhaps.
Hello.
Can I help you with something?
Considering what I'd like help with,
probably not.
[Frederick] Hmm.
[music stops]
Hello.
-I'm sorry about this morning.
-What happened this morning?
I'm speaking of that rude gentleman
we encountered.
I'm not your older brother.
You don't need my protection.
In any event, you've never had trouble
speaking for yourself.
[chuckles]
No apology necessary.
It was clearly well intended.
Look, we haven't really
had a chance to talk.
I've lived with a thousand different
imagined versions of you over the years.
Some to rail against.
Some to cherish.
Likewise.
I didn't know if I'd ever see you again.
Or if you knew how much I cared.
I think I always knew.
There's no one quite like you.
And it's clear to me
that I want you in my life.
No matter what form that takes.
Bury the past and…
I suppose what I'm getting at is, um…
I…
I would like to be friends.
[melancholic instrumental music]
I was… I was thinking the same.
I saw so clearly this morning the prison
my resentment had created.
I genuinely hope you find love
wherever you need to find it.
And I thank you,
from the bottom of my heart,
for your offer of friendship.
Thank you.
Well…
Excellent.
Good… talk.
[Anne] I really do hope you'll be open
to pursuing the admiralty.
Everyone speaks to your genius.
I'm sure they understate it.
They don't really know who I am
or what would make me happy.
Well, I do.
I know you.
And I know you want a life of consequence.
And I know you'd be brilliant.
-You want to know a secret?
-Always.
[both chuckle]
My most grim moments at sea,
when I felt completely lost and confused
and inadequate,
I would ask myself,
"What would Anne do here?"
That's how I'd know how to proceed.
Pretending I was you.
-You lie.
-I truth.
You're always best in an emergency.
Anticipating the needs of others.
Direct and focused, calm and thoughtful.
Equipped with more intelligence
than does you good.
No, you're an exceptional person.
It angers me the world denies you
the chance of a public life.
You'd make a great admiral.
Thanks.
Don't go out too far.
There's riptides and such.
Sorry. There I go
trying to protect you again.
As you were.
[Anne chuckles]
Now we're worse than exes.
We're friends.
[melancholic music]
[music continues]
[music stops]
Now you are in my way.
-Excuse me.
-Before you go,
allow me a proper introduction.
Or is your minder waiting round the corner
to tell me off again?
He's my friend,
and I believe
he misconstrued your intentions.
My intentions were construed
most accurately.
I intended for you to notice me.
Miss?
Miss.
-Simple. I like it.
-Mm-hmm.
Will I see you again?
We must entrust that to providence.
That means I haven't yet made up my mind.
What?
What is it, Anne?
[Anne] The man we passed yesterday.
Excuse me. Can you tell me the name
of the gentleman who just left?
That's Mr. William Walter Elliot, miss,
en route to Bath.
Of course he drives off
just as I get to the window.
-A cousin?
-Not just a cousin, Henrietta.
Our father's heir.
We should write to Father at once.
That news would not be welcome,
Mary, as well you know.
-[Mary] He'll be furious.
-[Henrietta] What happened between them?
-My father and Mr. Elliot do not speak.
-[gasps]
-I love a little bit of family gossip.
-[Louisa] Tell us.
Mr. Elliot will inherit the baronetcy
and the estate no matter what.
Father was desperate
that he marry Elizabeth
to keep the title within his direct line.
[Anne] But he turned her down.
We learned that he had married
an American woman who nobody knew.
Father threw a platter of canapés
across the room.
-Wasn't Mr. Elliot in mourning clothes?
-His wife's dead.
You must hate him for all the
embarrassment he's caused your family.
Actually, so far
it's his most winning quality.
[romantic instrumental music]
He's a lucky man to have met Louisa.
Hmm. Has he said anything to you
about how he feels?
No, she has.
[woman] It's quite steep. Careful.
[Louisa laughs]
Thank you.
Do be careful.
-Catch me, Captain.
-[Frederick] Oh, goodness.
-[Louisa laughs]
-[Frederick] Oh.
[both laugh]
Okay, that was your warm-up. Once more.
No, Louisa, that's enough. No more.
I'm jumping, so either catch me or don't.
-Louisa!
-No, no, no, no.
-[Anne] No. Don't move her. Louisa?
Can you hear me? Uh, we need a doctor.
I'll go.
No, someone who knows the town.
Benwick, get a doctor.
-Hurry!
-[Anne] Louisa.
-Anne, tell me what can I do?
-Just be patient.
[Anne] She's still breathing.
It's all right, she's breathing.
[doctor] She's had
quite a severe concussion.
But I've seen far greater injuries
recovered from.
There's reason to be hopeful.
-Leave her to rest now.
-[Mrs. Harville] Yes.
-[doctor] She can stay here?
-Of course.
No, you've been so kind,
we can't continue to impose.
She'll stay as long as she needs.
Whoever doesn't mind a spot on the floor
is welcome to stay with her.
Anne should stay.
To assist you, Mrs. Harville.
No one so capable, so perfect as Anne.
-You will stay, won't you?
-Of course.
I can't bear to leave until she's awake.
[Frederick] I'll deliver news
to the Musgroves.
-Thank you.
Would you be so kind
as to escort Mary and Henrietta?
Escort me?
The children, Mary.
We can't have them stay
with my parents an extra night.
Nearly burned the house down last time.
Why should Anne stay?
Anne who means nothing to Louisa.
-Oh, Mary.
-It was my understanding, Mary,
that you suffered from an allergy
to houses of fewer than five servants.
Aren't you worried
you'll contract something?
I'm not leaving.
Have a good journey, Anne.
[sorrowful instrumental music]
It's not your fault.
You told her not to leap.
In words, yes.
-But in other ways…
-In other ways?
I led her to believe I was a person
who was prepared to catch her.
How exactly did you do that?
I knew she was infatuated
and yet did nothing to discourage her.
Clearly, it led to this.
Had this not occurred,
one can only imagine
what our lives might have been.
Now I'm responsible for her.
How do I tell her parents?
Calmly.
Be direct.
Offer whatever services
they may require of you.
[sorrowful music continues]
Good luck.
What will you do now?
I need to go to Bath.
Thank you.
For everything.
[sorrowful music continues]
How is it
that life can remain static,
almost obstinately resistant to any change
for years at a time, and then…
without warning become flooded
with so much newness
within the course of a few weeks?
It's impossible to recall life
before the torrents.
[Lady Russell] That poor girl.
How are her parents?
[Anne] In shock,
but trying to stay hopeful.
[Lady Russell] Well,
that's all they can do.
Now, where are they?
Where are they?
-It's fine, we don't need them.
-[sighs]
I wanted it to be perfect for you.
Don't be silly,
I'm happy just to be here with you.
No, no, no.
It's not a picnic without macaroons.
[Anne chuckles]
Henry would have thrown a fit
if they'd forgotten to pack the dessert.
Well, lucky for you,
I don't really care for macaroons.
-Hmm.
-And I'm not Henry.
No.
Nobody is.
Do you ever think
about spending time with someone else?
Several men have offered.
Do you know whose company I enjoy?
My own.
There's a reason widowed men die soonest
and unmarried women live longest.
We're great company.
But do you ever miss… company?
[chuckles]
Why do you think I take
so many European tours?
Lady Russell!
[Lady Russell laughs]
Shh.
[playful instrumental music]
I hope I haven't eaten too much.
There's sure to be a feast tonight.
We're to meet the famous Mr. Elliot.
But why is he courting Father's favor now?
Well, Elizabeth, of course, assumes
it is she who motivates him
with all of her charms.
Mr. Elliot has nothing to gain
from my father.
He is richer than him
and will inherit his title no matter what.
-He must be after something.
-Why are you so suspicious of him?
Because anyone that attractive
must have an angle.
-What are you keeping from me?
-I've seen Mr. Elliot.
And he's attractive.
Very attractive.
You met him?
In Lyme, though neither of us knew
who we were meeting.
-Do I sense a romance brewing?
-That's not going to happen.
-Because?
-Because he is a ten.
I never trust a ten.
Oh!
[Lady Russell] This is you.
[bells ringing]
[Anne] This is his idea of downsizing?
[Lady Russell] It's a start.
Don't make me.
Courage, ma chérie.
I'll see you tonight.
[playful instrumental music]
-Anne! I'm so happy to see you.
-What do you mean by that?
Mr. Elliot is on his way and I want him
to see what I look like next to you.
-It's good to be home.
-Just think.
He's been nursing a crush on me
for nearly a decade.
Poor man. How he must have suffered.
All the way through a marriage
he ran away from you to secure.
Isn't it mad? He must have presumed
I was out of his league.
I can't imagine any other reason.
I'm never quite sure
whether you're insulting me,
but I value your regard so little
that I don't mind either way.
Ah, Anne. Is that what you're wearing?
Mr. Elliot will be here any moment.
I was surprised, Father,
to learn how forgiving you've been
after all he made you suffer.
Suffer?
Well, there were many insults.
He denies making them.
Father, he made them to you.
He was very strong in his denial.
[knock on door]
Oh, that's him.
Get the door, Anne. And don't slouch.
Hurry up!
Gosh.
[sighs]
Thank you.
Ah.
It seems like providence
plays for my team after all.
I'm your cousin, Anne.
Cousin? Interesting.
It's a decided step up from passerby,
but still a bit short of "most beloved".
But I am willing to work for my titles.
Imagine my luck,
a flirt and a hard worker.
Don't forget rich.
Lucky we have you to remind us.
What in God's name is happening?
Don't worry, darling,
he's just practicing on me.
Shall we?
[piano music]
[piano music in the room]
[clears his throat]
I understand you've been visiting
my sister quite often.
She is delighted by the attention.
Well, it's nice to hear
that your sister is capable of delight.
But romance has been
the last thing from my mind.
Until today.
[laughs]
Well, if you haven't been coming
for the purpose of courtship, then…
-[Elliot] Mrs. Clay, of course.
-Mrs. Clay?
About a month ago, I received word
that my uncle had appeared in Bath
in the company of a woman of low birth.
Many presumed she was after his hand.
Now, that marriage would be a scandal.
You're concerned
for my father's reputation?
Oh, no, not at all.
My concern is that he will have a son
and that son will rob me of my title
and my estate.
And my plan is to block that
by any means necessary.
I told you,
I'm willing to work for my titles.
[Anne chuckles]
I have to say,
I am impressed by your openness.
Refreshing, yes?
I'm so glad to see you again.
I heard about that terrible accident
that befell your party after I left Lyme.
How is she?
She's still confined to her bed,
but much recovered.
I received word this morning.
Thank you for asking.
-You must have suffered terribly.
-I suffered the least, truly.
You have a gentle soul.
You feel deeply for those around you.
I imagine it was quite an ordeal.
I regret you had to go through it.
Thank you.
[piano stops]
[guests applaud]
So good, darling.
Mm.
-Go forth. You have my blessing.
-I wouldn't do anything without it.
[chuckles]
-Bravo!
[Elliot] Bravo. Very well played, madam.
He means to disarm me with candor.
It isn't working. [chuckles]
Yet.
Probably won't.
Right?
Ow.
[munches]
[Sir Walter hums]
[screams]
-What?
-Joy.
Pardon me, I'm experiencing joy.
The dowager Viscountess Dalrymple
and her daughter,
the honorable Miss Carteret,
are in Bath.
[squealing]
Do you rehearse this stuff
while I'm sleeping?
Our dear cousins!
Cousins? I love cousins!
Cousin is a term most accurately applied
to those within one's family tree,
not those within one's family forest.
The Dalrymples don't have
the slightest notion that we exist.
With the help of a few visual aids,
I bet we could explain the connections
most comprehensively
within three quarters of an hour.
-But why?
-[Sir Walter] Why?
These people are nobility.
Everyone will want to be seen with them.
What's the advantage
of being seen with them?
Anne, don't be deliberately dense.
Quick! Break out your finest frocks.
We are about to touch… greatness.
[silence]
[clock ticking in the room]
[bird cooing outside]
[teaspoon clinking]
[birds chirping]
[slurps]
Sometimes, I have this dream
that a giant octopus is sucking my face
and, as I struggle to get free,
I realize that my, my hands are tentacles
and I can't push it off.
And then I realize, of course, that I am
the octopus, and I am
sucking my own
face.
[ticking continues]
Much like in life.
So often those we perceive
as our greatest adversaries
are just shadow versions of ourselves.
Well put, Mr. Elliot.
Hmm.
Perhaps the next time
you meet an octopus, Miss Elliot,
you should embrace him,
rather than try to detach.
Wrap those wily tendrils right around him
and let yourself be taken.
[chuckles]
In your dreams, Mr. Elliot.
And also in mine.
It was on account of eating some cheese
a bit too close to bedtime.
-Oh.
-Well, that went splendidly.
I knew it would. [laughs]
Your charms are irresistible, Sir Walter,
even to nobility. [laughs]
Your noble relations disappoint you.
[sighs]
That awful woman
cannot marry your father. Ugh.
[Anne] Tell me something.
You'd honestly rather prevent Mrs. Clay
from taking my father's arm
than talk with me?
My dear octopus, it's not even close.
You know…
you're beginning to grow on me.
Now I'm suspicious.
[playful instrumental music]
[Elliot] Fascinating.
[Lady Russell giggles]
Must everyone be interesting?
[Anne] Not at all. They are free
to be as boring as they like
so long as I am not asked
to sit with them.
And him?
[Anne chuckles]
He provided some relief.
More than I anticipated.
[Lady Russell] Hmm.
He spoke quite highly of you to me
the other night.
I believe there is some attachment.
Mr. Elliot could attach to a potato
if it suited him.
Though Elizabeth may find
some satisfaction living at home forever,
that life will lock you in deadness.
All I'm saying is,
I hope you will accept Mr. Elliot
if he makes an offer.
Based on your extensive knowledge of him?
I may not have extensive knowledge of him,
but I have extensive knowledge of you.
Not only is he rich and well-mannered,
I believe you've taken an interest in him.
I would never have recommended it
otherwise.
I'll admit, there is something there.
But, for once, I'm asking you to trust
that I have the resources
to make my own decisions.
I must rely on the instructions
issued by my own heart.
I tried the alternative once
and I'll never forgive myself for it.
You mean you'll never forgive me.
I just thought, under the circumstances…
Circumstances?
[Lady Russell] The engagement, of course.
Wentworth and Louisa.
Oh, I thought you knew.
Everyone is talking
about Louisa and her captain.
Oh, darling.
What can I do?
[exhales] I'd just like to be alone.
Well, I'm here when you want me.
[sorrowful instrumental music]
[music continues]
[shuddering breaths]
I always imagined myself
confronting this moment
with grace.
I would astonish myself and others
with my…
My quiet dignity.
My ability to endure.
Statues would be erected in my name.
"In memory of Anne Elliot,
who suffered cosmic loss
yet really held it together
quite impressively."
[sighs]
[music builds]
[music slows down, then stops]
Mm.
Anne.
-You're here.
-Yes, it appears I am.
-Are you alone?
-Mm.
I'm just waiting for a friend.
I see.
We got caught in the rain.
He's gone to fetch a carriage.
He's quite charming.
-Well, I'm pleased to hear that.
-He makes me laugh.
It's nice to laugh. [laughs]
Apparently, you've yet to hear
about the engagement. I'm--
I'm sorry, the horses
were a nightmare in the rain.
-Uh, Mr. Elliot, allow me to introduce--
-We remember each other.
We do.
[Elliot] Mm.
[exhales]
Th-this is Captain Wentworth.
Yes, your good friend Captain Wentworth.
I'm glad to have the opportunity
to, uh, apologize for my behavior in Lyme.
It was on account of being struck by this
dazzling creature.
Please don't call me a creature.
This dazzling, um…
[Anne] Woman? Woman?
-What's wrong with creature?
-We'll talk about it later.
What is taking you two so long?
Um, just one second. One second.
There's a concert tomorrow.
Will you join us?
-Oh, I'd hate to intrude.
-On what?
You'll come, then. Excellent.
We'll be a foursome.
You, she, the bel canto and me.
He's quite original, isn't he?
Unique, even.
It's good to see you happy.
Thanks.
I hope you're happy too.
Anne, I think we should be going.
I'll see you tomorrow.
[Elizabeth] Anne! Hurry up!
[melancholic music builds]
[overlapping chatter]
[quiet laughter in the room]
Good evening.
Shall we?
How's Louisa?
Very much recovered.
And yet still healing slowly.
It's going to take time and love
to see her through.
Good.
So long as you're in Bath,
I hope we can see a bit of one another.
I'm actually not sure
how long I'll be here.
I'm in the throes of a difficult decision.
Been offered a position aboard a ship.
Oh.
She sets sail for Malta Saturday,
so I don't have long to make up my mind.
-Well, that sounds exciting.
-Indeed it does.
I love my work and I'm happy
for the opportunity to serve, but--
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but I need to steal my Anne for a moment.
Fluent in Italian too,
would you believe it?
-Uh, we need help translating the program.
-Just one moment.
Anne, we need you to do Italian
for our cousins.
I do hope you'll be able
to make it to the wedding.
Anne would be devastated
if you weren't there.
I know how much
she values your friendship.
[stringed music]
[indistinct chatter]
[sings in Italian]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[singing continues]
Frederick!
I was hoping we could continue
our conversation.
Sadly, I'm not sure
there will be another opportunity.
I've just made up my mind. I'm off to sea.
Much to put in order before Saturday.
I'm sorry, I'm interrupting again.
No, no, no.
I'm afraid it is I who is interrupting.
Enjoy the second act.
[Mr. Elliot] We will.
-I didn't mean to upset--
-If you would just let me speak.
You interrupted me.
Let me say what's on my mind first.
I'm new to these genuine feelings.
I'm trying to learn from you, for you.
You're far too good for me
and I'm terrified.
But I want very much to make you my wife.
Nothing else would make me happier.
-Your wife?
-Yes. You don't have to answer now.
But please, think on it.
[music and singing continue]
The captain was right, you know.
The gentleman is indeed unique.
[music and singing fade]
[loud knock on door]
Ow.
Charles, hurry up!
[Mary groans]
The journey gave me dead leg.
I need you to massage it.
Mary, what are you doing here?
Uh, coming to fetch you, of course.
You need to come to the inn
with Charles and me to listen to me talk.
We're here for a little visit.
Ever since Louisa's accident,
life just seems so fragile and fleeting.
It's made me realize how important it is
to spend time away from one's children.
And it's dreadfully unfair that you
and Elizabeth are up here gallivanting
with Mr. Elliot and our noble cousins
and I haven't even been introduced
to them yet,
despite being the most accomplished
decoupage artist of the three of us. Hmm?
Oh, Anne, have you heard?
Louisa will marry a sailor
and Henrietta that soiled napkin
of a curate, Henry Hayter.
Mary, remember your list.
Oh, right.
My doctor thinks I might benefit
from embodying gratitude.
So every time something terrible
happens in my life,
I'm to think up something I'm glad for.
For example, the fact that both my sisters
are madly in love and about to be married?
No, that does nothing for me.
Well, I'm delighted for them both.
And I will come and visit later.
-Where are you going?
-[Anne] Um…
I have plans.
What plans?
Upstairs? You don't even have any friends
and all your relations are in this house.
I hate to agree with my wife, Anne,
but I've been given explicit instructions
not to return to the inn without you.
It'll be a little Lyme reunion.
Captain Harville was quite charmed by you
and delighted for the prospect
of renewing your acquaintance.
He's gone to fetch Wentworth just now.
How unfortunate you have other plans.
[indistinct chatter]
Anne.
I've missed you.
[Harville] We need to give Wentworth
a proper send-off.
[Charles] Absolutely.
A few drinks, a game of cards.
Although I understand
Anne has other plans.
I'm no card player.
Worst I've ever seen.
That was then. Time makes many changes.
I'm not yet so much changed.
Wentworth, sorry to interrupt
but I will not rest
until that letter is signed
and delivered to Admiral Croft.
You've been very slippery
these past few months.
Of course.
Are we finished?
I suppose so.
I'll be just a moment.
You look a bit sad, Captain Harville.
Well, actually, I should be happy.
Captain Benwick has found love at last.
That's wonderful.
I should think you would be pleased.
You were so determined
to see him out of his misery.
But I hadn't anticipated
the effect it would have on me.
It's as if his suffering
was keeping my sister alive somehow.
Poor Fanny. She would never
have forgotten him so soon.
Well, that's certain.
We women do not forget you
so soon as you forget us.
Women love beyond all sensible limits.
We cannot help ourselves.
I don't mean to venture any claims about
the differences between men and women.
[Anne] Oh, well, I will.
The only privilege I claim for my sex
is that of loving longest.
Loving even when hope is gone.
Loving because you don't have a choice.
-[Frederick] I'm finished.
-[Harville] Thank you.
[chuckles]
There is no quarreling with you.
I think Fanny would be happy
to see her Benwick cared for.
[Harville] Fanny was never
the jealous type.
In moments I've wondered if it wasn't
my sister's spirit in the wind
that caused Louisa to slip,
knowing somehow
eventually where she would land.
Louisa?
I've told you,
the universe has perfect timing.
And when you had the presence of mind
to tell Benwick to fetch a surgeon,
you must have had no idea the wheels
that you were setting in motion.
Captain, I'm afraid I'm lost.
I'm speaking of Louisa's engagement
to Captain Benwick, of course.
A love grown slow and sure
from his constant attention
to her during her convalescence.
Of what did you think I was speaking?
I don't know.
[Harville] I'll make sure
this letter gets to Admiral Croft.
"Dear Anne…"
[soft instrumental music]
"…I can listen no longer in silence."
"Anne, you pierce my soul."
"Dare not say
that man forgets sooner than woman,
that his love has an earlier death."
"I am half agony, half hope."
"I know you are to marry Mr. Elliot,
but I will never forgive myself
if I do not tell you this."
"You alone have brought me to Bath."
[gasps]
"For you alone I think and plan."
"But of course you have not seen this.
How could you?"
"Because your love has not lasted
as long as mine."
"Anne…
I have loved no one but you."
"And I don't think I ever will."
[music rises]
Anne.
-I can explain--
-I wish you both every happiness. [laughs]
[Frederick] "I have thought many times
about how to tell you,
but the pain of a love unrequited
rendered me silent."
"Tell me not that I am too late."
Frederick!
[Frederick] "My love for you
has never faltered."
[music slows down]
[birds sing]
["Quietly Yours" by Birdy plays]
♪ White sails and offshore lights ♪
♪ We were passing ships in the night ♪
♪ Now I'm tracing shadows on your back ♪
♪ Like I dreamt so many times ♪
♪ Oh, for so long, I've been waiting ♪
♪ For so long, for a love like this ♪
♪ And I was so sure, baby,
I'd lost you for a minute, but ♪
♪ There's the sweetest ♪
♪ Spring at my door ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ Just the same as before ♪
♪ Many years have gone by ♪
♪ But I knew you'd come ♪
♪ I've always been yours ♪
♪ Only yours, mmm ♪
[instrumental continues]
[Anne] There are many kinds of love.
For some, the right partnership
can be a lucrative endeavor.
For others,
true connection is reward enough.
♪ Quietly yours… ♪
[whispers] Where are they?
[Anne] It's okay to find love
on your terms…
however unorthodox.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh… ♪
Don't let anyone tell you how to live.
Or who to love.
I learned the hard way.
[song stops]
Tilt the sextant until the image
of the sun kisses the horizon.
[Anne] Right, lined up.
That angle is called your sight.
We would normally take a note of that.
Using various mathematical equations and
accounting for the height of the cliff,
we can estimate our latitude.
That's all?
Well, I won't tell anyone
how painfully easy nautical navigation is.
It might tarnish the Navy's reputation.
Well, on behalf of the Crown,
we thank you for your discretion.
[chuckles]
I was thinking, perhaps we can enjoy
a quick anchoring in Venice
before Constantinople?
Do you know what it takes
to turn a ship around?
Yes.
From personal experience.
["Quietly Yours" by Birdy continues]
♪ There was a time when I let you go ♪
♪ Allowed myself to be swayed and pulled ♪
♪ But for all my days, I make a vow ♪
♪ No words could ever shake me now ♪
♪ 'Cause for so long, I've been waiting ♪
♪ For so long, for a love like this ♪
♪ And I was so sure, baby,
I'd lost you for a minute, but ♪
♪ There's the sweetest ♪
♪ Spring at my door ♪
♪ Can you feel it? ♪
♪ Just the same as before ♪
♪ Many years have gone by ♪
♪ But I knew you'd come ♪
♪ Quietly keeping ♪
♪ This hope in my heart ♪
♪ Prayed the night bring ♪
♪ Back what I lost ♪
♪ Many years have gone by ♪
♪ I never forgot ♪
♪ I've always been yours ♪
♪ Only yours ♪
♪ Quietly yours ♪
♪ I've always been yours ♪
♪ Only yours ♪
♪ Quietly yours ♪
♪ Only yours, mmm ♪
[soft instrumental music plays]
[romantic instrumental music plays]
[romantic instrumental music fades]